Italian Painting Photograph Collection
Yale University Arts Library
Italian Painting Photograph Collection
1900-2005
VRC 23
Yale University Arts Library
88.75
213 boxes
Collection of mounted black and white and color reproductions of Italian paintings, predominantly from the 13th-16th centuries. Some materials have been transferred to and are available at the Yale University Art Gallery, please also consult the companion finding aid, "Italian Painting Photograph Collection: Materials Available in the Yale University Art Gallery." see VRC 23.1. Content Varies from original photographic prints to reproductions from magazines and other published sources. Some sections have accompanying clippings folders.
Conditions Governing Access
These materials are stored offsite at the Library Shelving Facility. For access to the materials, please make a request at the Art & Architecture Library.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically by individual artist name. The individual artist section is further sub-divided primarily by location of work. The individual artist portion is preceded by an Anonymous grouping arranged chronologically.
Scope and Contents
Collection of mounted black and white and color reproductions of Italian paintings, predominantly from the 13th-16th centuries. Some materials have been transferred to and are available at the Yale University Art Gallery, please also consult the companion finding aid, "Italian Painting Photograph Collection: Materials Available in the Yale University Art Gallery." see VRC 23.1. Content Varies from original photographic prints to reproductions from magazines and other published sources. Some sections have accompanying clippings folders.
Painting, Italian; Photographs; Reproductions
- Anonymous. (Box 1)
  - Miscellany., 10 (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Includes a folder of miscellaneous clippings.
  - Account books., 12 (Box 1)
  - XI Century., 6 (Box 1)
    - Various locations., 2 (Box 1)
    - S. Angelo in Formis., 4 (Box 1)
  - XII Century., 13 (Box 1)
    - Various locations., 9 (Box 1)
    - Master Guiliemus, 4 (Box 1)
  - XIII Century., 115 (Box 1)
    - Crucifixes., 17 (Box 1)
    - Frescoes., 26 (Box 1)
      - Various locations., 11 (Box 1)
      - Assisi., 12 (Box 1)
      - San Gimignano., 3 (Box 1)
    - Panel Painting., 44 (Box 1)
    - General Masters., 4 (Box 1)
    - Isaac Master., 6 (Box 1)
    - Magdalen Master., 13 (Box 1)
    - Master of St. Martin., 5 (Box 1)
  - XIV Century., 154 (Box 1)
    - Drawings., 7 (Box 1)
    - Crucifixes., 9 (Box 1)
    - Frescoes., 39 (Box 1)
      - Various locations., 16 (Box 2)
      - Ajaccio., 3 (Box 2)
      - Pisa, Campo Santo., 5 (Box 2)
      - Subiaco, Sacro Speco., 18 (Box 2)
    - Panel Painting., 50 (Box 3)
    - General Masters., 19 (Box 3)
    - Master of the Ovile Madonna., 15 (Box 3)
    - Master of the Citta di Castello., 8 (Box 3)
    - Master of the St. George Codex., 7 (Box 3)
  - XV Century., 209 (Box 3)
    Includes two folders of miscellaneous clippings.
    - Drawings., 19 (Box 4)
    - Paintings., 187 (Box 4)
      - General Paintings., 25 (Box 4)
      - Florentine School., 39 (Box 4)
      - Cassoni., 47 (Box 5)
        - General Works., 22 (Box 5)
        - Anghiari Master., 4 (Box 5)
        - Master of the Bambino Vispo., 5 (Box 5)
        - Master of the Berenson Annunciation., 7 (Box 5)
        - Master of the Castello Nativity., 9 (Box 5)
      - North Italian School., 20 (Box 5)
        - General Works., 16 (Box 5)
        - Master of the Louvre Predella., 4 (Box 5)
      - Sienese School., 36 (Box 5)
        - General Works., 31 (Box 6)
        - Master of the Griggs Tondo., 6 (Box 6)
      - Umbrian School., 16 (Box 6)
      - Venetian School., 6 (Box 6)
  - XVI Century., 59 (Box 6)
    - General Works., 22 (Box 6)
    - Florentine School., 19 (Box 6)
    - Umbrian School., 4 (Box 7)
    - Venetian School., 14 (Box 7)
  - XVII Century., 16 (Box 7)
  - XVIII Century., 6 (Box 7)
  - XX Century., 1 (Box 7)
- A (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous Artists A., 26 (Box 7)
    - Afro, 1912-., 2 (Box 7)
    - Alberti, Cherubino, 1552-1615., 1 (Box 7)
    - Alamanno, Pietro, active c.1478., 2 (Box 7)
    - Alfani, Domenico, 1479-1553., 2 (Box 7)
    - Allegrini, Francesco, 1587-1663., 1 (Box 7)
    - Amadei, Giuliano, 1446-1496., 1 (Box 7)
    - Amidano, Giulio Cesare, 1566-1630., 1 (Box 7)
    - Angeli, Giuseppe, 1709-1798., 1 (Box 7)
    - Ansuino da Forli, active mid-XV Century., 2 (Box 7)
    - Fra Antonio da Bologna, active c.1550., 3 (Box 7)
    - Antonio da Crevalcore, active 1478., 1 (Box 7)
    - Antonioli, Raffaele, ?., 1 (Box 7)
    - Appiani, Andrea, 1754-1817., 3 (Box 7)
    - Araldi, Alessandro, 1460-1528., 1 (Box 7)
    - Arcangelo di Cola da Camerino, active 1416-1429., 2 (Box 7)
    - Aretusi, Pellegrino, 1465-1523., 2 (Box 7)
  - Individual Artists A., 770 (Box 7)
    - Abbati, Giuseppe, 1836-1868., 6 (Box 7)
    - Abbate, Niccolo dell', 1512-1571., 8 (Box 8)
    - Albani, Francesco, 1578-1660., 34 (Box 8)
    - Albertinelli, Mariotto, 1474-1515., 10 (Box 8)
    - Allori, Alessandro, 1535-1607., 15 (Box 8)
    - Allori, Cristofano, 1577-1621., 6 (Box 8)
    - Altichieri, Altichiero, active 1369-1388., 14 (Box 9)
    - Alunno, Niccolo da Foligno, c.1430-1502., 15 (Box 9)
    - Amigoni, Jacopo, 1675-1752., 6 (Box 9)
    - Andrea da Firenze, active 1343-1377., 54 (Box 9)
      - Miscellaneous Works., 2 (Box 9)
      - Florence, S. Maria Novella., 46 (Box 9)
      - Pisa., 6 (Box 10)
    - Andrea di Bortolo, active 1389-1426., 17 (Box 10)
    - Andrea di Giusto, 1440-1498., 15 (Box 10)
    - Andrea da Murano, c.1462-1502., 3 (Box 10)
    - Andrea di Niccolo, 1460-1529., 7 (Box 11)
    - Angelico, Fra, 1387-1455., 391 (Box 11)
      Includes a large folder of miscellaneous clippings.
      - Miscellaneous Works., 8 (Box 11)
      - Miscellaneous Cities., 32 (Box 11)
      - Antwerp., 4 (Box 11)
      - Boston., 6 (Box 11)
      - Cortona., 26 (Box 11)
      - Florence., 193 (Box 11)
        - Miscellaneous Locations., 14 (Box 11)
        - San Marco., 177 (Box 11)
          - Missals., 3 (Box 11)
          - Frescoes., 69 (Box 11)
          - Panel Paintings., 85 (Box 11)
          - Silver Chest Panels., 20 (Box 11)
      - London., 5 (Box 11)
      - Montecarlo., 7 (Box 11)
      - New York., 6 (Box 11)
      - Orvieto., 6 (Box 11)
      - Paris., 24 (Box 11)
      - Perugia., 10 (Box 11)
      - Rome., 49 (Box 11)
      - Washington, D.C., 15 (Box 11)
    - Anguissola, Sofonisba, 1528-1625., 4 (Box 11)
    - Antonella da Messina, 1430-1479., 83 (Box 12)
    - Antoniazzo Romano, active 1460-1508., 23 (Box 12)
    - Antonio da Negroponte, XV Century., 4 (Box 12)
    - Antonio Veneziano, 1313-1387., 4 (Box 12)
    - Appolonio di Giovanni, XV Century., 29 (Box 12)
    - Arcimboldo, Giuseppe, 1530-1593., 13 (Box 12)
    - Aspertini, Amico, 1475-1552., 9 (Box 12)
- B (Box 12)
  - Miscellaneous Artists B., 98 (Box 12)
    - Bacciarelli, Marcello, 1731-1818., 2 (Box 12)
    - Badalocchio, Sisto, 1581-1647., 1 (Box 12)
    - Badile, Giovanni Antonio, 1516-1560., 1 (Box 12)
    - Bagnacavallo, Giovanni Battista, 1521-1601., 2 (Box 12)
    - Baldessari, Roberto Iras, 1894-., 1 (Box 12)
      May be the same as Roberto Marcello Baldessari.
    - Baldessari, Roberto Marcello, 1894-1968., 1 (Box 12)
      May be the same as Robero Iras Baldessari.
    - Baldi, Lazzaro, 1624-1703., 1 (Box 12)
    - Balducci, Giovanni, active 1550-1600., 2 (Box 12)
    - Balestra, Antonio, 1666-1740., 1 (Box 12)
    - Banti, Christiano, 1824-1904., 1 (Box 12)
    - Bandini, Giulia, XVIIII Century., 1 (Box 12)
    - Barbalonga, Antonio, 1600-1649., 1 (Box 12)
    - Barbelli, Giovanni Giacomo, 1590-1656., 1 (Box 12)
    - Bardi, Donato Conte de', active c.1426-1461., 1 (Box 12)
    - Baroccio, Federigo, 1526-1612., 1 (Box 12)
    - Bartolomeo di Tomasso, active 1425-1451., 1 (Box 12)
    - Bassano, Francesco, 1549-1592., 3 (Box 12)
    - Il Bastianino, ?., 1 (Box 12)
    - Battaglioli, Francesco, active 1750., 1 (Box 13)
    - Bellinzoni, Giovanni Antonio, c.1415-1478., 1 (Box 13)
    - Belvedere, Andrea, 1642-1732., 1 (Box 13)
    - Bembo, Bonifacio, active 1475., 1 (Box 13)
    - Benedetto di Bindo, active c.1414., 2 (Box 13)
    - Benefial, Marco, 1684-1764., 4 (Box 13)
    - Benvenuti, Pietro, 1769-1844., 1 (Box 13)
    - Bernardino di Mariotto, 1497-1566., 2 (Box 13)
    - Bernardo di Giovanni del Guasta, XV Century?, 1 (Box 13)
    - Il Bertoja, 1544-1574., 2 (Box 13)
      Also known as Jacopo Zanguidi.
    - Bertucci, Giovanni Battista, active 1503-1516., 1 (Box 13)
    - Bettera, Bartolomeo, late XVI Century., 2 (Box 13)
    - Bevilacqua, Ambrogio Filippo, XV Century., 1 (Box 13)
    - Bianchi, Isidoro, 1581-1662., 1 (Box 13)
    - Bianchi, Mose, 1840-1904., 5 (Box 13)
    - Bianchi Ferrari, Francesco de', 1460-1510., 1 (Box 13)
    - Bigari, Vittorio Maria, 1692-1776., 4 (Box 13)
    - Biliverti, Giovanni, 1576-1644., 2 (Box 13)
    - Biscaino, B., 1632-1657., 1 (Box 13)
    - Bisi, Bonaventura, 1612-1659., 1 (Box 13)
    - Blaas, Giulio de, 1845-1934., 2 (Box 13)
    - Boateri, Jacopo di, XV Century., 1 (Box 13)
    - Boccaccino, Camillo, 1501-1546., 1 (Box 13)
    - Bocchi, Faustino, 1659-1742., 1 (Box 13)
    - Boetti, Alighiero, 1940-., 1 (Box 13)
    - Bominaco, XIII Century., 1 (Box 13)
    - Bonamici, L., XX Century., 1 (Box 13)
    - Bonascia, Bartolommeo, 1450-1527., 2 (Box 13)
    - Bonito, Giuseppe, 1707-1789., 1 (Box 13)
    - Bono da Ferrara, active 1450-1461., 2 (Box 13)
    - Bononi Carlo, 1569-1632., 3 (Box 13)
    - Bonzi, Pietro Paolo, 1573-1633., 2 (Box 13)
    - Boscoli, Andrea, 1550-1606., 3 (Box 13)
    - Bossi, Guiseppe, 1777-1815., 1 (Box 13)
    - Bottani, Guiseppe, 1717-1784., 4 (Box 13)
    - Bragadin, Donato Bernardo di Giovanni, active 1438-1473., 1 (Box 13)
    - Brandi, Giancinto, 1623-1691., 2 (Box 13)
    - Brescianino, Andrea del, active 1507-1525., 2 (Box 13)
      Also known as Andrea Piccinelli.
    - Brumidi, Constantino, 1805-1880., 1 (Box 13)
    - Bruni, Fedor Antonvitch, 1801-1874., 1 (Box 13)
    - Brusaferro, Girolamo, 1700-1760., 1 (Box 13)
    - Brusasorci, Domenico, 1516-1567., 2 (Box 13)
    - Bueno, Antonio, 1918-., 2 (Box 13)
    - Buontalenti, B., 1536-1608., 1 (Box 13)
    - Bulgarini, Bartolomeo, active 1345-c.1378., 1 (Box 13)
  - Individual Artists B., 1817 (Box 13)
    - Bacchiacca, Francesco Ubertino, 1494-1557., 12 (Box 14)
    - Baglione, Cavaliere Giovanni,1571-1644., 5 (Box 14)
    - Baldovinetti, Alesso, 1425-1499., 43 (Box 14)
      - Various locations., 13 (Box 14)
      - Florence., 30 (Box 14)
    - Balducci, Matteo, 1509-1554., 4 (Box 14)
    - Balla, Giacomo, 1871-1958., 16 (Box 14)
    - Bandinelli, Baccio, 1488-1560., 7 (Box 15)
    - Barbari, Jacopo de, c.1440-c.1516., 12 (Box 15)
    - Barna da Siena, active 1369-1380., 4 (Box 15)
    - Barnaba da Modena, 1364-1383., 5 (Box 16)
    - Barocci, Federico, 1526-1612., 37 (Box 16)
      - Drawings., 22 (Box 16)
      - Paintings., 15 (Box 16)
    - Baronzio, Giovanni, -1362., 6 (Box 16)
    - Bartoli di Fredi, 1330-1410., 38 (Box 17)
    - Bartolommeo, Fra, 1472-1517., 62 (Box 17)
      - Drawings., 32 (Box 17)
      - Paintings., 30 (Box 17)
    - Bartolomeo di Giovanni, active 1488-c.1500., 10 (Box 18)
      Includes a folder of miscellaneous clippings
    - Bartolomeo Veneto, active 1502-died 1531., 23 (Box 18)
    - Basaiti, Marco, c.1480-c.1530., 10 (Box 18)
    - Baschenis, Evaristo, 1617-1677., 5 (Box 18)
    - Bassano, Jacopo, 1510-1592., 61 (Box 18)
      - Drawings., 11 (Box 18)
      - Paintings., 50 (Box 19)
    - Bassano, Leandro, 1557-1622., 8 (Box 19)
    - Bastiani, Lazzaro, before 1430-1512., 4 (Box 19)
    - Batoni, Pompeo, 1708-1787., 49 (Box 20)
    - Bazzani, Giuseppe, 1690-1769., 7 (Box 20)
    - Beaumont, Claudio Francesco, 1694-1766., 5 (Box 20)
    - Beccafumi, Domenico di Pace, 1486-1551., 64 (Box 20)
      - Drawings., 9 (Box 20)
      - Paintings., 45 (Box 20)
        - Miscellaneous Collections., 13 (Box 20)
        - Pisa., 7 (Box 20)
        - Siena., 25 (Box 20)
    - Bella, Stephano della, 1610-1664., 6 (Box 21)
    - Bellini, Gentile, 1429-1507., 42 (Box 21)
      - Drawings., 5 (Box 21)
      - Paintings., 37 (Box 21)
    - Bellini, Giovanni, 1430-1516., 199 (Box 21)
      - Drawings., 6 (Box 21)
      - Paintings., 193 (Box 21)
        - Locations not noted., 16 (Box 21)
        - Miscellaneous cities., 45 (Box 22)
        - London., 32 (Box 22)
        - Milan., 13 (Box 23)
        - New York., 14 (Box 23)
        - Venice., 53 (Box 24)
        - Washington, D.C., 20 (Box 24)
    - Bellini, Jacopo, 1400-1470., 26 (Box 24)
      - Drawings., 8 (Box 24)
      - Paintings., 18 (Box 25)
    - Bellotto, Bernardo, 1720-1780., 44 (Box 25)
      Also known as Canaletto.
    - Benozzo, Gozzoli, 1420-1497., 112 (Box 25)
      - Drawings., 5 (Box 25)
      - Paintings., 107 (Box 25)
        - Miscellaneous locations., 26 (Box 26)
        - Florence., 31 (Box 26)
        - Montefalco., 9 (Box 26)
        - Pisa., 20 (Box 26)
        - San Gimigniano., 21 (Box 27)
    - Benvenuto di Giovanni, 1436-1518., 25 (Box 27)
    - Berlinghieri, Bonaventura, active 1228-1244., 17 (Box 27)
    - Bernini, Giovanni Lorenzo, 1598-1680., 21 (Box 27)
      - Drawings., 14 (Box 27)
      - Paintings., 7 (Box 27)
    - Besozzo, Michelino Molinari da, 1404-1442., 2 (Box 27)
    - Biagio d'Antonio da Firenze, active 1476-1504., 7 (Box 27)
    - Bianchi-Ferrari, Francesco, 1460-1510., 6 (Box 28)
    - Bibbiena, Giuseppe Galli, 1696-1756., 7 (Box 28)
    - Bicci di Lorenzo, 1373-1450., 16 (Box 28)
    - Bissolo, Francesco Pietro, 1492-1554., 4 (Box 28)
    - Boccaccino, Bocaccio, 1467-1524., 11 (Box 28)
    - Boccati, Giovanni da Camerino, 1420-1480., 11 (Box 28)
    - Boccioni, Umberto, 1882-1916., 28 (Box 29)
    - Boldini, Giovanni, 1842-1931., 50 (Box 29)
    - Bologna, Giovanni da, 1524-1608., 3 (Box 29)
    - Boltraffio, Giovanni Antonio, 1467-1516., 30 (Box 30)
    - Bonfigli, Benedetto, active 1445-1496., 36 (Box 30)
    - Bonifazio Veronese, 1487-1553., 14 (Box 30)
      Also known as Bonifazio Veneziano.
    - Bono, Michele di Taddeo, c.1420-1462., 13 (Box 30)
    - Bonsignori, Francesco, 1455-1519., 8 (Box 31)
    - Bordone, Paris, 1500-1571., 25 (Box 31)
      - Drawings., 3 (Box 31)
      - Paintings., 22 (Box 31)
    - Borgianni, Orazio, 1578-1616., 6 (Box 31)
    - Borognone, Ambrogio, c.1455-1535., 32 (Box 31)
    - Borrani, Odoardo, 1833-1903., 6 (Box 31)
    - Bossoli, Carlo, 1815-1884., 8 (Box 32)
    - Botticelli, Sandro, 1444/5-1510., 308 (Box 32)
      - Drawings., 14 (Box 32)
      - Paintings., 294 (Box 32)
        - Locations not noted., 16 (Box 32)
        - Miscellaneous cities., 23 (Box 32)
        - Berlin., 15 (Box 32)
        - Boston., 4 (Box 32)
        - Florence., 118 (Box 32)
          - Miscellaneous locations in Florence., 8 (Box 32)
          - Ognissanti., 6 (Box 32)
          - Pitti Palace., 11 (Box 32)
          - Uffizi., 93 (Box 32)
            - Miscellaneous paintings., 18 (Box 32)
            - Adoration of the Magi., 16 (Box 32)
            - Birth of Venus., 20 (Box 32)
            - The Calumny of Apelles., 11 (Box 32)
            - Coronation of the Virgin., 5 (Box 32)
            - Madonna of the Magnificat., 7 (Box 32)
            - Madonna of the Pomegranite., 5 (Box 32)
            - S. Barnabas Altarpiece., 11 (Box 32)
        - Frankfurt., 5 (Box 32)
        - London., 30 (Box 32)
        - Milan., 8 (Box 32)
        - New York., 8 (Box 32)
        - Paris., 8 (Box 32)
        - Philadelphia., 6 (Box 32)
        - Rome., 41 (Box 32)
        - Washington, D.C., 12 (Box 32)
    - Botticini, Francesco, 1466-1497., 24 (Box 32)
    - Bramante, Donato, 1444-1514., 19 (Box 32)
      - Drawings., 3 (Box 32)
      - Paintings., 16 (Box 32)
    - Bramantino (Bartolommeo Suardi), act. 1503-1536., 19 (Box 32)
    - Brea da Nizza, Ludovico, c.1443-1523., 7 (Box 33)
    - Bronzino, Angolo, 1503-1572., 103 (Box 33)
      - Drawings., 3 (Box 33)
      - Paintings., 100 (Box 33)
        - Locations not noted., 9 (Box 33)
        - Miscellaneous cities., 25 (Box 33)
        - Florence., 31 (Box 34)
        - London., 14 (Box 34)
        - New York., 8 (Box 34)
        - Rome., 8 (Box 34)
        - Washington, D.C., 5 (Box 34)
    - Bugiardini, Giuliano di Piero di Simone, 1475-1554., 8 (Box 34)
    - Buonconsiglio, Giovanni, active 1465-1535/7., 3 (Box 34)
    - Burri, Alberto, 1915-1995., 7 (Box 34)
    - Butinone, Bernardino, c.1450-c.1507., 7 (Box 35)
- C (Box 35)
  - Miscellaneous Artists C., 102 (Box 35)
    - Caletti, Giuseppe, c. 1600-1660., 1 (Box 35)
    - Caliari, Carlo, 1570-1596., 3 (Box 35)
    - Calosci, Arturo, 1854-1935., 1 (Box 35)
    - Calvart, Dionisio, 1540-1619., 1 (Box 35)
    - Cammarano, Michele, 1835-1920., 1 (Box 35)
    - Campi, Vincenzo, 1536-1591., 1 (Box 35)
    - Camuccini, Vincenzo, 1771-1844., 1 (Box 35)
    - Canguillo, Francesco, 1888-., 1 (Box 35)
    - Canlessi, Guido, 1601-1681., 1 (Box 35)
    - Cannicci, Niccolo, 1846-1906., 1 (Box 35)
    - Cantagallina, Remigio, c.1582-1630., 1 (Box 35)
    - Cantarini, Simone, 1612-1648., 2 (Box 35)
    - Canute, Domenico Maria, 1620-1684., 2 (Box 35)
    - Cappiello, Leonetto, 1875-., 1 (Box 35)
    - Capogrossi, Guiseppe, 1900-., 1 (Box 35)
    - Caporali, Bartolomeo, 1442-c.1505., 2 (Box 35)
    - Caprioli, Domenico, 1494-1528., 1 (Box 35)
    - Carena, Felice, 1879-1966., 2 (Box 35)
    - Cariani, Giovanni de' Busi, 1485/90-after 1547., 4 (Box 35)
    - Carlandi, Onorato, 1848-1939., 1 (Box 35)
    - Carnovali, Giovanni (il Piccio), 1806-1873., 4 (Box 35)
    - Caroselli, Angelo, 1585-1652., 1 (Box 35)
    - Carpi, Girolamo da, 1501-1556., 1 (Box 35)
    - Carpione, Giulio, 1611-1674., 2 (Box 35)
    - Carraci, Lodovico, 1555-1619., 3 (Box 35)
    - Casali, Andrea, 1720/24-1783., 1 (Box 35)
    - Cascella, Michele, 1892-1989., 1 (Box 35)
    - Caselli, Cristoforo, c.1460-1521., 1 (Box 35)
    - Catarino and Donato, XIV Century., 1 (Box 35)
    - Cavagna, Giovanni Paolo, 1556-1627., 1 (Box 35)
    - Cavallon, Giorgio, 1904-., 1 (Box 35)
    - Cavallucci, Antonio, 1752-1795., 1 (Box 35)
    - Cavedone, Giacomo, 1577-1660., 3 (Box 35)
    - Cecco di Pietro, 1370-1402., 2 (Box 35)
    - Ceccobelli, Bruno, 1952-., 2 (Box 35)
    - Ceciono, Adriano, 1838-1886., 1 (Box 35)
    - Cellini, Benevenuto, 1500-1571., 2 (Box 35)
    - Cerquozzi, Michelangelo, 1602-1660., 3 (Box 35)
    - Cesari, Giuseppe, 1568-1640., 4 (Box 35)
    - Chia, Sandro, 1946-., 3 (Box 35)
    - Chimenti, Jacopo, 1554-1640., 4 (Box 35)
    - Chini, Galileo, 1873-1956., 1 (Box 35)
    - Cicognara, Antonio, active 1480-1500., 1 (Box 35)
    - Ciglio, Ludovico Cardi, 1559-1613., 1 (Box 35)
    - Cignani, Carlo, 1628-1719., 1 (Box 35)
    - Cione, Andrea di, 1308 (?)-1368., 1 (Box 35)
      Photo also labeled "Traini"
    - Ciseri, Antonio, 1821-1891., 2 (Box 36)
    - Codazzi, Viviano, 1611-1672., 2 (Box 36)
    - Colantonio, Niccolo Antonio, active 1420-1460., 1 (Box 36)
    - Commodi, Andrea, 1560-1638., 1 (Box 36)
    - Conte, Jacopino del, 1510-1598., 1 (Box 36)
    - Conti, Primo, 1900-., 1 (Box 36)
    - Corenzio, Baldassare, 1558/60-1640/43., 2 (Box 36)
    - Corradini, Mara, XVIIII Century?, 1 (Box 36)
    - Corrodi, Herman David Solomon, 1844-1905., 1 (Box 36)
    - Corvi, Dominico, 1721-1803., 2 (Box 36)
    - Costa, Giovanni, 1826-1903., 5 (Box 36)
    - Costanzi, Placido, 1690-1759., 1 (Box 36)
    - Costanzo, Marco, XV Century., 1 (Box 36)
    - Cozzarelli, Giacomo, 1453-1515., 1 (Box 36)
    - Cremonini, 1926-., 1 (Box 36)
    - Creti, Donato, 1671-1749., 1 (Box 36)
    - Cristoforo da Bologna, active c.1380-1410., 1 (Box 36)
  - Individual Artists C., 2031 (Box 36)
    - Cabianca, Vincenzo, 1827-1902., 7 (Box 36)
    - Cades, Giuseppe, 1750-1799., 3 (Box 36)
    - Cagnacci, Guido, 1601-1681., 6 (Box 36)
    - Cairo, Francesco del, 1598-1674., 3 (Box 36)
      Also known as Il Cavaliere.
    - Caliari, Benedetto, 1538-1598., 7 (Box 36)
    - Cambiaso, Luca, 1527-1585., 12 (Box 36)
    - Camerino, Arcangelo di Cola da, active 1416-1429., 5 (Box 36)
    - Campagnola, Domenico, 1482-1562., 48 (Box 36)
      - Drawings., 8 (Box 37)
      - Paintings., 40 (Box 37)
    - Campi, Giulio, 1502-1572., 4 (Box 37)
    - Campigli, Massimo, 1895-1971., 20 (Box 37)
    - Canal, Antonio, 1697-1768., 147 (Box 37)
      - Drawings., 23 (Box 38)
      - Paintings., 124 (Box 38)
        - Locations not noted., 31 (Box 38)
        - Private collections., 12 (Box 38)
        - Miscellaneous cities., 46 (Box 38)
        - London., 16 (Box 39)
        - School of Canaletto., 19 (Box 39)
    - Canova, Antonio, 1757-1822., 4 (Box 39)
    - Capanna, Puccio, active 1350., 3 (Box 39)
    - Capponi, Raffaellino di Bartolommeo, c.1456-1524., 14 (Box 39)
    - Caracciolo, Giovanni Batista, 1578-1635., 11 (Box 40)
    - Caravaggio, Michelangelo, 1571-1610., 207 (Box 40)
      - Unnamed private collections., 1 (Box 40)
      - Miscellaneous cities., 57 (Box 40)
      - Berlin., 9 (Box 40)
      - Florence., 17 (Box 41)
      - London., 9 (Box 41)
      - Milan., 6 (Box 41)
      - Naples., 7 (Box 41)
      - New York., 6 (Box 41)
      - Paris., 9 (Box 41)
      - Rome., 75 (Box 42)
      - Attributed to Caravaggio., 11 (Box 42)
    - Cariani, Giovanni Busi, c.1480-post 1548., 13 (Box 42)
    - Carlevaris, Luca, 1665-1731., 6 (Box 43)
    - Carnevale, Fra Bartolommeo, active 1451-1484., 5 (Box 43)
    - Caroto, Francesco, c.1480-1546., 3 (Box 43)
    - Carpaccio, Vittore, c.1460-1522., 130 (Box 43)
      - Drawings., 10 (Box 43)
      - Paintings., 120 (Box 43)
        - Unnamed locations., 6 (Box 43)
        - Miscellaneous cities., 26 (Box 44)
        - Venice., 78 (Box 45)
        - Washington., 10 (Box 45)
    - Carra, Carlo, 1881-1966., 50 (Box 45)
    - Carracci, Agostino, 1551-1602., 9 (Box 46)
    - Carracci, Annibale, 1560-1609., 84 (Box 46)
      - Drawings., 16 (Box 46)
      - Paintings., 68 (Box 46)
        - Miscellaneous locations., 15 (Box 46)
        - Dresden., 6 (Box 46)
        - London., 13 (Box 46)
        - Paris., 4 (Box 46)
        - Rome., 21 (Box 47)
        - Leningrad., 4 (Box 47)
        - Washington, D.C., 5 (Box 47)
    - Carracci, Ludovico, 1555-1619., 20 (Box 47)
      - Drawings., 7 (Box 47)
      - Paintings., 13 (Box 47)
    - Carriera, Rosalba, 1675-1757., 16 (Box 47)
    - Casorati, Felice, 1883-1963, 2 (Box 47)
    - Castagno, Andrea del, 1390-1457., 136 (Box 47)
      - Miscellaneous locations., 9 (Box 48)
      - Florence., 118 (Box 48)
        - Miscellaneous churches., 4 (Box 48)
        - Cathedral., 8 (Box 48)
        - Ss. Annunziata., 19 (Box 49)
        - S. Apollonia., 77 (Box 50)
      - Washington, D.C., 9 (Box 50)
    - Castello, Valerio, 1625-1659., 6 (Box 50)
    - Castiglione, Giovanni Benedetto, 1616-1670., 9 (Box 50)
    - Catena, Vincenzio di Biago, 1470-1531., 16 (Box 50)
    - Cavallini, Pietro, 1250-1330., 13 (Box 50)
    - Cavallini, Pietro, School of., 7 (Box 51)
    - Cavallino, Bernardo, 1622-1654., 10 (Box 51)
    - Ceccarelli, Naddo, active 1347., 6 (Box 51)
    - Cenni, di Francesco di Ser Cenni, active 1369-1415., 11 (Box 51)
      See also Cennino Cennini for Legend of the Cross, Volterra.
    - Cennini, Cennino, late XIV C.-early XV C., 16 (Box 51)
      See also Cenni di Francesco di Ser Cenni for Legend of the Cross, Volterra.
    - Ceruti, Giacomo, active c.1720-1750., 8 (Box 51)
    - Cesare da Sesto, 1477-1523., 5 (Box 51)
    - Chiari, Guiseppe Bartolomeo, 1654-1724., 4 (Box 51)
    - Chirico, Giorgio de, 1888-1978., 125 (Box 51)
      - Drawings., 15 (Box 52)
      - Paintings., 110 (Box 52)
        - Location not noted., 27 (Box 52)
        - Private collections., 38 (Box 52)
        - Miscellaneous cities., 21 (Box 52)
        - New York., 19 (Box 53)
        - Philadelphia., 5 (Box 53)